<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Esteban Ramos on esteban</title>
    <link>https://example.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Esteban Ramos on esteban</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pictures Taken in Santa Cruz County</title>
      <link>https://example.org/photography/santa-cruz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/photography/santa-cruz/</guid>
      <description>This is were I dump pictures that I take while biking around Santa Cruz, California.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Split gRPC: An Isolation Architecture for RPC Stacks on SmartNICs</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/talk_compute_io/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/talk_compute_io/</guid>
      <description>It was an absolute pleasure to attend the Computational IO Workshop. Lots of great talks and great work presented!&#xA;Talk + Slides&#xA;Talk Blurb Remote procedure calls are a major contributor to performance variance in distributed systems due to lack of isolation and contention on shared resources. In this talk, I will introduce the novel architecture we built to address this problem, and cover our experience in implementing a prototype over gRPC with an emphasis on the communication layer between a host CPU and the SmartNIC.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portland Trip</title>
      <link>https://example.org/photography/trip-portland/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/photography/trip-portland/</guid>
      <description>I took the Amtrack up to Portland! Lovely trip.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why can’t we just use the interpreter sometimes?</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/compilersproject/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/compilersproject/</guid>
      <description>This project was completed as part of CSE-211 with Tyler Sorenson. Thanks for the great class!&#xA;It is not a controversial statement that we care very deeply about performance. The programs that we write must run efficiently on a diverse set of hardware whose local software state can be equally as diverse. Similarly, program behavior varies over its lifetime, evolving workloads result in very different &amp;ldquo;hot spots&amp;rdquo; in both instruction execution and memory usage in our programs.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
